Expect the impossible again.
Mission: Impossible II is a adventure, action,
thriller film directed by John Woo.
With computer genius Luther Stickell at his side and a beautiful thief on his mind, agent Ethan Hunt races across Australia
and Spain to stop a former IMF agent from unleashing a genetically engineered biological weapon called Chimera.
This mission, should Hunt choose to accept it, plunges him into the
center of an international crisis of terrifying magnitude.
Ethan Hunt, played by Tom Cruise.
Sean Ambrose, played by Dougray Scott.
Nyah Hall, played by Thandiwe Newton.
Luther Stickell, played by Ving Rhames.
Hugh Stamp, played by Richard Roxburgh.
Billy Baird, played by John Polson.
Mission: Impossible 2 (titled onscreen as Mission: Impossible II and abbreviated as M:i-2) is a 2000 action spy
film directed by John Woo from a screenplay by Robert Towne, and produced by and starring Tom Cruise.
It is a standalone sequel to Mission: Impossible (1996) and the second
installment in the Mission: Impossible film series.
The film also stars Dougray Scott, Thandiwe Newton, Richard Roxburgh, John
Polson, Brendan Gleeson, Rade Šerbedžija and Ving Rhames.
In the film, Ethan Hunt (Cruise) teams with professional thief Nyah Nordoff-Hall (Newton) to secure a genetically modified disease,
Chimera, held by rogue Impossible Missions Force (IMF) agent Sean Ambrose (Scott), who is Nordoff-Hall's former lover.
Mission: Impossible 2 was theatrically released in the United States by Paramount Pictures on May 24, 2000,
and grossed over $546 million worldwide, becoming the highest-grossing film of that year.
It received mixed reviews from critics, with praise for the action sequences
and Woo's direction, but criticism for the characterization.
A third film, Mission: Impossible III, was released in 2006.
The film explores themes of dying and death, mask, island,
central intelligence agency (cia), helicopter.
The tone is intense.